A glacier in Antarctica bleeds red, and the water pouring out has been trapped underground
for over a million years.
It's called Blood Falls on Taylor Glacier in the McMurdo Drive alleys.
Beneath it sits a saltwater lake, sealed under ice for around 1.5 million years.
In 2017 geochemist Jill McCookie confirmed the red color comes from iron in that brine.
Iron that's slowly dissolved from bedrock in a completely oxygen-free environment.
The moment that iron-rich water hits open air, it rusts instantly, so the glacier isn't
bleeding.
It's oxidizing in real time, and that sealed lake underneath?
It still contains living microbes, surviving with no light, no oxygen, and almost no heat.
Hello for one real fact today.